The truth is that quite a lot of you
should be trying to get new coaching
clients without using social media.
I know I'm always banging on about
funnels, email lists, landing pages,
but some of
you are in the infancy of your business
where you want to migrate to online, but
you still need in-person coaching clients
to pay the bloody bills.
Now, although I love online freedom,
working from Bali, I also
love how easy it is to get a client
face-to-face, because let's be honest,
for most
of you, to get your first online client,
you're three months of work away.
So we need people to walk in the door
tomorrow.
This is why it's tragic
that so many personal trainers want to go
straight to
online when they realize they could
literally walk the floor for two hours
and pick
up a high-paying client. So did a post
and someone commented on it
and it triggered
me. Shock. So I was trying to say
that flyering, yes, giving out
flyers could be a powerful tool for 2026.
And someone said,
"Bro bankrupt his business buying 100
coffees in this
economy." I'm going to explain.
So I think flyering could be fantastic for
you. Sport massage therapist,
maybe even an accountant,
personal trainer,
life coach, whatever it is you do.
Electrician, landscape gardener,
insert profession. Now,
first things first, any of you that think
that you have the design skills to create
a flyer, you don't. You don't.
If someone picks up a poorly designed
flyer, they're going to think, well,
if the
massage or the landscaping
is anything like this,
it's going to be Didier dog
shit. Pay a graphic designer
or get AI to do it. Nothing in between.
You getting some Times New Roman on a
black background and a picture of you that
you learnt how to remove background on
Canva is not good enough.
It's like turning up to a job interview in
a gimp suit and hoping for the best.
Now,
one of the first things we need to play
into is familiarity.
Some of you may not know this, but
when you have a certain car,
let's say you've
got a BMW M3 or a Volkswagen Golf,
you're more inclined to let
out people with the same car at a junction
because you're, oh, a Golf boy. Hey.
Same way that when you go on holiday to
Benidorm, knowing you, you meet someone,
you're like, "Oh, where are you from?"
And they're like, "I'm from Frome." You're
like, "What? Where Frome, Frome? Mum, Dad,
they're from Frome." Who's from
Frome? I don't know.
Because they're from the same area,
you're friends
automatically. Doesn't matter
if they look like pedos. Doesn't matter.
You're from the same area,
you're now bezzies on holiday.
So play into familiarity.
Some of the copy
that I'd love to see on a flyer is,
"Hi, my name's Lindsay.
I'm a sport massage therapist.
I work out of this facility or this gym,
and I live over on Abbott Street." Because
if you're going to fly within, let's say,
a kilometer to begin with, people are
like, "Oh, I know Abbott Street.
My nan lives on Abbott Street. Oh, yeah.
God, Abbott Street.
Used to hang out there as a kid."
And then they read the rest.
Such an ability because
if you're in their gym
or you know the area, because say,
"I live a two-minute walk from this pub."
"Oh, I know that pub." Straight away,
that part of the brain
that softens them up from familiarity
activates.
You're not just a pleb putting paper
through the letterbox trying to get their
money. You're a local. Now,
some of you out there want to work with
parents, busy
professionals, all of that, whatever.
Take the familiarity to the next step.
When you're going to do the flyering,
you can pay the post office to do it,
most of
you. But you could put something in there.
"Hope you don't mind
that one of my sons put this through your
letterbox." "Oh,
they've got kids as well.
They understand me.
They know the problems I'm going through.
They know how stressed I am for
that deep tissue massage,
Lindsay." "We was
flyering with my daughters this morning.
Hope you don't mind this has come through
your letterbox." Straight away.
I've got daughters, too.
Thinking local business, family. God.
Abbott Street.
I'm just making this up,
but you get what I'm saying, right?
Rather than please do business with me
or get 10% off with this QR code,
communicate and look like a fucking normal
human being because if someone at the
local bakery was to go, "Oh, this
is Lindsay,
she's a sport massage therapist." She
wouldn't go, "Hello, scan this QR code,
get 10% off." You go, "Oh yeah,
I live just
down the road. These are my daughters.
This is Kate and this is Rebecca.
Lovely to meet you. Yeah.
If you want to book one in,
you can have the first one
free." Whatever it is, we need
that messaging on the flyer.
Then there is an opportunity to have
banter in there.
I don't do Hyrox,
I don't take pictures of myself topless at
the gym, and
I hate it when people give their dogs
human names.
Why is your dog called Clive?
Someone looks at that,
they have a little laugh.
They go, "Do you know what? I hate it
when people give their dog a human name
because they're calling for the dog,
'Rupert!' And you think they've lost their
fucking granddad." You're like, "Oh,
we best go help them find Rupert.
He's probably a World War II vet stuck
face down in a fucking swamp." "Who's
Rupert?" "Oh, it's my chihuahua." Why
are you calling a chihuahua Rupert?
Fuck me.
Now,
even if you're not interested in flyering,
just listen to this.
Be fucking creative. If you
were to go to your local coffee shop,
you could have a
chat with the owner,
or you could just go in there,
chat to the staff.
"I want to buy 100 coffees,
please." "Cool. What's a coffee? £3.50.
£350." You're going to pay for it with
your business debit card.
You could ask for an invoice
if you wanted.
And you say, "Look,
the next 100 people
that come in for a coffee, I want to buy
their coffee.
And all I want them to do in return
is to take a flyer.
They don't even have to get in contact
with me.
That's the deal." So then as people come
into the local cafe and they go, "Oh yeah,
flat white, please. Oh actually,
can I get a flat white and an Americano?
Sure." "Oh by the way,
a local coach came in this morning.
He said he'll pay for your coffees,"
or she'll pay for your coffees.
"Just got to take a flyer." "What?" "Yeah,
yeah.
He came in, he bought 100 coffees." "Oh,
okay." Get the flyer.
"Oh, I know Abbott Street.
My sister-in-law lives there. Oh, too,
yeah.
Do you know what? Thanks."
If someone bought me...
Someone paid for my petrol the other day.
Max Cleans. I need to message him.
I said, "Bro, do you know what?
I'm going to give you tickets to Chris's
live show.
I'm going to send you Nutonic
when it lands in Australia
and I'm going to take your
mum out for a drive." His return on
investment of paying for me flipping
petrol is
tenfold. Put him on the stories.
I feel forever in his debt.
If someone was to sneak attack me
and buy me a coffee, I would 100% be
contacting that person just through the
law of reciprocity.
It was a bit of fun and do you know what?
I go, "Do you know what?
I like it." I had a lad come knock on my
door wanting to clean my car.
He cleaned my car.
He's now on my mentorship.
He did 80K in a month recently.
That's AUD, so that's £40,000 in a month.
So even if you leave this video not
creating flyers,
think about things that you can do
that are just a little bit outside the
box.
And then someone there, that comment,
they go, "Oh, you bankrupted yourself."
£350 is not a lot through Facebook ads,
right?
For a start. So that £350, 100 coffees,
one client
comes to you.
You don't just get the amount
that client pays you.
So the amount that the client pays you
is what you charge.
But then you have the average customer
value,
which is how many times they see you.
Now, for a sport massage therapist,
let's say again, £40 a massage.
I don't know. They see you 10 times.
You got your money back.
But most people are probably going to see
you, I don't know, once a week, once a
fortnight indefinitely.
So you have to understand what
is the average customer
value, but also what
is the cost per acquisition?
Because if 100 flyers equals one client,
your cost per acquisition is 350.
Average customer value is 400. That
is a net positive effect,
albeit of only £50.
But then the 99 people
that had a free coffee
that didn't get in touch,
they're there. When they pull their back,
they've got your flyer.
When their friend goes,
"I need a sport massage therapist," they
have your flyer
and they're not just going to go,
they're going to go, "Oh,
it's a funny little
lad, lives on Abbott Street.
He did this thing with a local cafe.
Bloody wonderful.
Ended up... Yeah, I don't need it,
but perfect for you." You're generating
goodwill.
It's the exact same thing we do with
content on social media.
We want to get in people's good books,
so the day that a fucking button pops off
on
their jeans, they're thinking of you
and your name and not someone else's.
The same part of your brain
that gets creative thinking,
"I'm going to make a video
that no one else has done.
I'm going to make it better than anyone
else." Do you
understand how little competition there
is To create a flyer that
could benefit your brand, your business,
and to have the audacity to go buy people
coffee, it's fucking genius.
Going into local offices, doing
talks, putting yourself out there.
Back in 2014,
I walked door to door in the Bracknell
Business
Park near my gym.
So I'm a personal trainer from here.
I lied to them and said,
"I do talks on fat loss.
I'm offering them to local businesses.
The gym manager says it'll be good because
somebody might come join the gym.
So I'll come do it for free." First one I
did, 12 people came to it.
I was in the boardroom giving them a
little bit of a chat about calorie
deficit.
At the end, 10 left, two stayed,
wanted to know about PT.
Both of them signed up as clients,
£35 an hour.
£70 a week, ongoing, £280 a month.
It's nearly my gym rent from one
talk. Marketing. Be fucking creative.
Put some effort into it.
And if the 100 flipping flyers gets you
nothing, move on to someone else or pick
another coffee shop. But
if 100 flyers gets you four clients,
rinse and repeat.
And I hope you understand, this video
is not even about flyering.
This video is about being creative.
Again, back in the day,
went to the gym manager, pre-GDPR.
"Can I email the database introducing
myself?" When you are given emails,
illegally or not, do not sell to them.
"My name's John.
I'm a personal trainer.
I specialize in fat loss
and muscle growth." Say, "Hello,
my name's John. I'm new to the gym.
Just wanted to let you know that
if there's
anything you need help with,
here's my mobile number, here's my email.
I'm not going to pressure you into doing a
PT session.
I'm just genuinely keen to help.
If you see me around, please come
and introduce
yourself. And truth be told,
I'm brand new.
I've got a lot of time on my hands.
If you want to do a free session,
I'd love to do it.
Not so I can close you as a client.
I just think it'd be good for other people
to
see how amazing a coach I am.
Drop me a message. No hard feelings.
Whether you want to learn how to squat in
the squat rack, do a lunge properly or
whatever, I'm here for you.
Feel free to drop me a text
or a voice note.
Open to everything. Cheers,
John." People are not idiots and they
are receptive
to good marketing,
such as face-to-face marketing.
That'll work for now, but
if you want something
that can work in the background,
the best employee that I've ever had
is social media because I chuck up a video
like this one and it generates me sales
ongoing.
To find out how we do that,
there's a link in the description.
You can do my short-form content mastery,
it's $99.
My silver play button to learn how to grow
on YouTube, it's 199.
And I got my business mentorship
and some other stuff.
But even if you don't buy that,
just be more fucking creative. All right?
Bye-bye.